The simulator data consists primarily of images.
模拟器数据主要由图像组成
Before I start using this data to train a model,
在使用这些数据训练模型之前
I'd like to look at those images.
让我们看一下这些图像
I'll start by opening driving_log.csv.
首先打开 driving_log.csv.
Each line in this file represents a point in time
这个文件里的每行代表训练圈中的每个时间点
during my training lap, and each line has seven tokens.
每行有七项内容
I'm going to add labels to each column
接下来 我为这里的每一列打上标签
here so it's easier to see what each line represents.
这样可以更容易地看到每行内容分别代表什么
The first three tokens in each line
每行的前三项内容都是图像所在路径
are paths to images, one each for cameras
它们分别对应于
mounted on the center, left, and right of the vehicle's
安装在挡风玻璃中间、左侧和右侧的三个摄像头
windshield.
所拍摄的图像
The next four tokens are measurements for steering,
后四项内容是
throttle, brake, and speed.
转向角、油门、刹车和速度的值
The steering measurements range between negative 1 and 1.
转向角的区间为 -1 到 1
The throttle measurements range between 0 and 1.
油门的区间为 0 到 1
The brake measurements seem to all be 0,
刹车的值似乎全部为 0
and the speed measurements range from 0 to 30.
速度则为 0 到 30
The throttle, brake, and speed data
油门、刹车和速度数据
could all be useful for training the network,
都可以用来训练网络
but for now, I'm going to ignore them.
但在这里 我暂时不使用这些数据
I'll start by using the images as the feature
首先 我会把这些图像用作特征集
set and the steering measurements as the label set.
把转向角用作标签集
Then I'll use the images to train the network
然后用这些图像训练网络
to predict the steering measurements.
来预测转向角
This is the very first image in the data set.
这是数据集中的第一张图像
It's taken from a camera mounted in the center
它是位于挡风玻璃中间的摄像头所拍摄的
of the windshield, and I can see the hood of the car peeking out
可以看到图像底部的
from the bottom of the image.
汽车引擎盖
The image is 160 pixels wide by 320 pixels high,
图像高度为 160 像素 宽度为 320 像素
and of course, it's three channels deep
这是一张 RGB 图像
because it's an RGB image.
它有三个颜色通道
The top portion of the image seems
图像顶部似乎
to capture hills and trees and sky, elements
拍到了山丘、树木和天空
that might distract the model more than help it.
这些内容对模型不仅没有帮助 反而可能带来干扰
At some point, it might make sense
从某种角度考虑 把图像顶部裁减掉
to crop off that top portion of the image.
是一种合理的做法
Here are the left and right images
这里是左侧和右侧摄像头所拍摄的图像
that correspond to that center image for the very first line
时间点对应于
in the CSV file.
CSV 文件第一行的中间摄像头所拍摄的图像
All of these images capture a similar scene
三幅图像都包含类似的场景
but from slightly different positions.
只是角度稍有不同
You might wonder why the simulator gives us three camera
你可能想知道 为什么模拟器在每个时间点
shots for each point in time.
提供了三个摄像头所拍摄的图像
The reason is that we can use these camera shots to help
原因在于 多个摄像头的数据
us generalize the model.
可以更好地泛化模型
Effectively, we can pass these images
实际上 我们可以把这些图像
to the network to teach the network what
输入网络 教会网络
it looks like to be off the center of the road
偏离道路中心的是什么样子
and how to steer to get back to the center.
以及如何打方向盘以回到道路中心
I'll talk more about this later.
我会在后续课程中详细讨论这些内容